Can you keep a secret?
A Simple Favor is a thriller, comedy, mystery film directed by Paul Feig.
Stephanie, a dedicated mother and popular vlogger, befriends Emily, a mysterious
upper-class woman whose son Nicky attends the same school as Miles, Stephanie's son.
When Emily asks her to pick Nicky up from school and then disappears, Stephanie
undertakes an investigation that will dive deep into Emily's cloudy past.
Stephanie Smothers, played by Anna Kendrick.
Emily Nelson, played by Blake Lively.
Sean Townsend, played by Henry Golding.
Dennis Nylon, played by Rupert Friend.
Diana Hyland, played by Linda Cardellini.
Detective Summervile, played by Bashir Salahuddin.
A Simple Favor is a 2018 American black comedy mystery film directed by Paul Feig from a
screenplay by Jessica Sharzer, based on the 2017 novel by Darcey Bell.
It stars Anna Kendrick, Blake Lively, Henry Golding, and Andrew Rannells, and follows a small-town vlogger
(Kendrick) who tries to solve the disappearance of her elegant and mysterious friend (Lively).
The film's development began in 2016 when 20th Century
Fox bought the rights to the novel.
The following year, it was moved to Lionsgate with Feig hired to direct
while Kendrick and Lively were cast in the leading roles.
Filming took place in Toronto, Ontario and began on February 2017.
A Simple Favor was released theatrically by Lionsgate in
the United States on September 14, 2018.
The film was met with a favourable response for its plot twists and
performances (especially that of Kendrick, Lively, and Golding).
It grossed $97.6 million worldwide on a $20 million budget.
A sequel, Another Simple Favor, was released on Amazon Prime Video on May 1, 2025, with
Kendrick and Lively reprising their roles, and Feig returning as director.
The film explores themes of small town, based on novel or
book, widow, dark comedy, female friendship.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and intense.